No matter how far you go, you never forget where you came from.
Belfast is a drama, history film directed by Kenneth Branagh.
Buddy is a young boy on the cusp of adolescence, whose life is filled with
familial love, childhood hijinks, and a blossoming romance.
Yet, with his beloved hometown caught up in increasing turmoil, his family faces a momentous
choice: hope the conflict will pass or leave everything they know behind for a new life.
Buddy, played by Jude Hill.
Pa, played by Jamie Dornan.
Ma, played by Caitríona Balfe.
Will, played by Lewis McAskie.
Granny, played by Judi Dench.
Pop, played by Ciarán Hinds.
Belfast is a 2021 coming-of-age drama film written
and directed by Kenneth Branagh.
The film stars Caitríona Balfe, Judi Dench, Jamie Dornan,
Ciarán Hinds, Colin Morgan and Jude Hill.
The film, which Branagh has described as his "most personal", follows a young boy's
childhood in Belfast, Northern Ireland, at the beginning of The Troubles in 1969.
Belfast had its world premiere at the 48th Telluride Film Festival on 2 September 2021; shortly
thereafter, it won the People's Choice Award at the 2021 Toronto International Film Festival.
The film was released in the United States on 12 November 2021 by Focus Features, and in
the United Kingdom and Ireland on 21 January 2022, by Universal Pictures.
It received generally positive reviews from critics for Branagh's direction and screenplay,
cinematography, and the performances of the cast, and grossed $49 million worldwide.
The film received seven nominations at the 94th Academy Awards,
including Best Picture, winning for Best Original Screenplay.
It was named one of the best films of 2021 by the National Board of Review and tied with The Power of the Dog for a leading seven
nominations at the 79th Golden Globe Awards, including Best Motion Picture – Drama, and won for Best Screenplay.
It also tied with West Side Story for a leading eleven nominations at the 27th Critics' Choice Awards, including Best Picture,
and also received six nominations at the 75th British Academy Film Awards, winning Outstanding British Film.
The film explores themes of working class, black and white, belfast,
north ireland, 1960s, the troubles (north ireland, 1966-98).
The tone is emotional.